Have you ever stopped
and wondered to yourself why some people
post on social media
and some people don't? Why
is it some people have the incessant need
to document
every single part of their life? And
are they even doing this for themselves,
or
are they doing it for validation?
When they go on holiday,
are they taking pictures
of where they're staying
and posting it to share with loved ones,
or are they doing
it to make other people jealous?
Are they getting more enjoyment of their
time at
the festival or more enjoyment of filming
it and making other people feel like
they have the fear of missing out?
There are groups of people
that need to share
everything they do in their lives,
but the majority of people don't feel
that need.
And if you're watching this video
and you lean towards the side of not
wanting to
make videos every day
and put it on the internet,
it could be because you're
mentally sound and
that you don't need external validation
from others.
It could be that all the people winning on
social media have underlying
tones of narcissism
and get kicks out of making people
jealous.
And in this video,
we're going to look into the weird
psychology of people that
don't post on social media. And if you
are one of those people,
why potentially you
might want to make the change. Now,
quickly, my name's James Smith.
I unfortunately am a social media creator,
and I hate the word
influencer because I never really wanted
to do this.
And if it was up to me,
I wouldn't even be making this video
today.
The reason I'm here
is this video serves a purpose. It
is part of my work.
And the branding behind me,
if we sell that for a billion, I'm gone.
No more social media.
And the point of this video
is to educate you the point that
although I've posted to social media
thousands and thousands of
times, I don't do it because I want to.
I do it because it's the smartest,
highest leverage play and marketing
opportunity that our species have ever
created or stumbled
across. And to rewind a little bit,
back in 2014, 2015, I'm working in a
budget gym.
I know some of you have heard this story
before.
And it really sucks building a business on
a gym floor because you have to go up to
people that don't want to talk to you
and try and sell your services.
So I went to social media,
not because I was like, "Oh,
it'd be really cool to
write blogs on whether or not a potato
is better than a sweet potato,"
but because
I was desperate to not have to walk the
floor.
Then every evolution in my social media
since has been because I
don't want to go back to those exchanges.
And I don't think any social media
creator's ever saying to you,
"I'm not making
content because I enjoy it.
I'm making content because this
is how I run and
operate a business."
But don't feel sorry for me.
This model that I'm about to teach you
about means I spend more time with my
child
and partner than any father in history,
apart from the unemployed on some
benefits.
So let's take this away from me
and put it onto you.
You aren't posting social media
or not utilizing it enough because
you've probably got your shit together
and you're not mental.
But there's a paradox in that.
By being mentally sound
and not making content,
you're also being mental because you're
missing the biggest opportunity in
history.
And the only cost
that you have to give up is privacy
and embarrassment.
And if you can overcome that,
you can scale your business, your brand,
your hobby,
or whatever it is that you do.
So let's get into point one.
You are making excuses of privacy
or narcissism.
And it'd be worth noting
that you're probably right.
When you look at the social media
landscape of people posting
and talking about
their businesses or even doing what I'm
doing now,
you might think they're a bit of
a nob. And in some cases,
that's completely true.
But we need to look at the other end of
the spectrum.
Some people are trying to run
and operate a business, and any of the
perceived fame or status
is actually kind of beneficial to other
people. For that, I'm going to explain.
I'm going to show you.
The main premise of social media
is actually helping people.
That's how good content goes viral.
Often it is that
that point has helped someone maybe
understand something.
Maybe something's made clear,
something they feel compelled to share
or send to a
friend.
So if we can first see the premise of
social media, not about being fame or
wealth, but about helping people,
that's great.
Then the second thing we need to kind of
come to terms with is that just because
you help people doesn't mean they should
give you their money.
So we're going to look into something
that I call the attribution pyramid.
It's a very,
very simple thing to understand.
So this pyramid here represents the amount
of people that you could help online.
Now, I'm a believer
that only a very small percentage of those
people are ever
going to buy our stuff, and that is okay.
And if we can make content for everyone,
of which some people consider doing
business with us, that is a win.
And that's what I do.
Exactly this video today.
The backbone of this video
is to get people posting more on social
media so they
can start helping people with the skills
that they have.
Maybe you're a therapist,
maybe you're an accountant,
whatever it is.
And by giving value to you for free,
there is a chance that you would
do what I ask. For instance,
there's going to be a link in this
description.
I'm running a free three-day event for
business owners, content creators, and I'm
going to be teaching you everything you
need to do to get these three things:
better content, more leads, more money.
My fridge just started humming.
Trying to make a video, mate. Shut up.
Now,
the beautiful thing about this pyramid
is this.
One day,
you're going to be walking down the
street, and someone from this area,
FBE, I call it the fist bump effect.
They're going to be walking down the
street, they're going to shout your name,
and
they're going to go, "Oi, Sarah,
that video that you made about anxiety
really
helped me understand the psychological
trauma that I had with my mother
when I was
younger," or whatever it is.
These people are going to buy the thing
you're
selling, and they're going to love it,
and they're going to get great results.
But these people here
are also of tremendous value because even
though you're
helping them for free,
there's a high likeliness
that someone else within their
network, whether a brother, auntie,
daughter, sister, whatever,
is going to say,
"Wow,
I really need a good accountant."
And they go, "There's this person I follow
on social media. They're amazing." "Oh,
I'm thinking of starting therapy." "Oh my
God, have you seen this person online?
She runs this clinic.
It's really amazing for this reason."
And it's only through putting out the
content
for free that those people will even know
who you are or what you do or what you
sell or whatever. Social media
is your ability to almost do charity work
to the majority of people,
but it ends up being better than charity
because you get
to keep some of the money. And
that actually reminds me.
I've always had this idea
that with charity and fundraising and
GoFundMe or whatever it is,
let people keep 10% of what they earn
because
people are so inclined to work harder for
financial
incentive.
So if I'm going to raise 100K for charity,
if I'm allowed to
keep 10% of it, I'm raising 250.
I'm going to be pressuring people going,
"Come on,
brother, it's for charity.
Give it for charity.
You can afford more than that."
And that's in essence what this business
model is.
Now The other thing, especially
if you're from Britain,
there's something called
the zero-sum mentality. And what
that means is, if you get rich,
it's at the
expense of other people.
We can all agree that
if you want to be famous for the
sake of being famous,
you're a bit of a fucking bellend.
So if you're going to go on "Love Island"
just so you can get a million followers,
I'm sorry, but bellend. Sorry, Chris.
But to want to start a business in a bid
to help people, that's pretty noble, and
your aspirations shouldn't just be to make
100K a year.
In some respects,
it should be to be the best at what you
can do.
And I don't think it makes you a
narcissist if you put your hand up
and say, "I
want to be the best accountant that's ever
been on social media.
I want to be the best personal trainer
that ever did it." Because wanting
or being
to be super successful has a trickle-down
effect.
And there are days on social media
that I hate it.
There are days that people call me a
misogynist.
There are days that people call me
transphobic, and they could be right.
There are days that people call me all
kinds of things under the sun,
and I think,
"Why on earth am I doing this?
Why couldn't I just be living on..." I
was going to
say,
why couldn't I be living on 60K a year?
And then that would sound kind of
tone-deaf because that's still good money.
The reality is there's a really big
trickle-down effect
when you're good at stuff.
For instance, I employ people.
I pay people's wages.
People don't have to go to work
and punch in at an office because I employ
them.
Also, I pay a lot of tax. Now,
for every single
dollar that you see me flaunt on expensive
stuff, I
pretty much have to give another dollar
back to the Australian government
that goes
onto welfare.
So I'm now at a point in my life where the
more successful my brand
gets, the better the country performs.
So you need to rewire your brain
and your perception about social media,
about
getting big views,
about running a business,
about becoming a personal brand.
The more successful you become,
the more money you make,
the more opportunities
you create for yourself,
the more you create for other people
around you.
And that might not just be even the state,
the tax man, your clients.
It could also mean that in the future,
your husband or wife doesn't have to work,
and that your kids have some kind of level
of financial security.
But that could be a whole bloody video
altogether, because the more money I make,
the more I do worry that my son
is going to grow up to be a spoiled little
asshole,
let alone any other kids.
So you're in this dichotomy in life of I
want to be mega
successful, but with every leap
and step I make towards my own
success,
I could be ruining my son's future,
because he's never going to be as
successful as me. Let's face it.
It's a joke. Relax.
Now, there's a caveat to this.
If you're a nine-to-fiver, and again, some
people think I'm chatting shit
when I say nine-to-fiver.
Hey,
I miss those days of being in an office
where at 5:30,
when I left,
I didn't give a shit what happened.
I didn't care if someone died.
You could have told me on a Saturday
morning the business building burned down,
and
I wouldn't have given a shit till 9:00
a.m. on Monday.
So as a nine-to-fiver, there probably
is no need to post online.
And actually, the fact
that you can use social media less than
anyone else, because
the issue is, someone like me,
when I'm finding myself on social media,
I end
up telling myself it's work.
I'm doing market research.
I'm just figuring out what trends
and hooks are working for other people,
which a
nine-to-fiver don't have to worry about.
But if you run a business
and you're not utilizing social media,
you are
disrespecting yourself,
but you're also disrespecting people in
your organization.
Because if you were to have a few videos
that really boot off and perform well,
and it was to extrapolate,
not the right use of the word,
the income of the
business, that's bonuses for your staff.
That's better offices.
That's nicer amenities.
That's getting in a food service company
to stock your
fridges full of Nutonic.
You not maximizing your own business
potential and taking
ownership for creating content.
You're sat there thinking,
"I don't want to be a
narcissist.
I don't want to be judged." I'm sat there
going, "Why do you hate your
staff and your family
that you wouldn't use the biggest
opportunity since the
invention of electricity, which
is the internet?" You get to quite
literally
talk to lenses and make money,
and you're not doing it.
And that, guys, if you're being like, "Oh,
I'm not a narcissist," all of that,
you're scared, and it's okay,
and we're going to explain more in this
video.
Now, I won't lie, the privacy thing
is a bit mad. It's great in some respects.
You could be going into a club in Ibiza,
and someone's like, "Yo, love your stuff.
Queue jump.
Go to the front." You could be going
places. You get VIP. That's great.
But then a lot of people knowing your
personal life means that you can't drop a
pinger at a festival because the second
that pill kicks in and you start
gurning, people come over and go,
"You're the guy from Facebook." Things get
real
weird.
But although I've had to give up a lot of
privacy, I would say it's
benefited my life in lots
and lots of ways.
First of all, I'm a bit retarded,
and I've definitely got some
kind of pretty severe ADHD.
As you can tell,
I can't even stand still whilst
recording this video.
So my attention span
is all over the place.
Bing, bing, bing, bing, bing, bing, bing,
bing, bing.
So there are times in the day
that I'm productive, times in the day
that I'm not,
and now I'm actually going to go training
in a bit, and I just felt a wave of
productivity from the 400 milligrams of
caffeine that I had, and I was like, "Yo,
let's just talk about this."
But the money's good.
For instance, these
are titanium catalyst headers for a 992
GT3. They're the stock ones there.
I would have to work for eight months in
my old job
just to afford a set of these. So
if you do have a 992 GT3 and you
are thinking of
doing a custom exhaust with IPE
and you do want to go catalyst
and you're not
worried about the drone or the fact
that it's so loud
that you feel like you're
going to get an air bleed,
please contact me because I've got some
exhaust headers
for you. And literally,
for the price of those,
I could have got my car wrapped
again. I'm disgusted in myself.
There's a famous quote
that says you wouldn't
worry so much what other people thought
about you if you realized how
little and less often they do.
And it's true with content.
The biggest thing here is
if a video bombs, it bombs.
No one sees it.
There are mistakes
and bad things you can do in life.
For instance, if I go to the pub
and I neck 10 pints
and I decide to drive home,
that's a pretty life-changing,
significant, terrible mistake.
If I decided in my younger years to shoot
my load in the wrong woman, that
is a pretty big life mistake.
If you go to a brass house
in Colombia and end up barebacking your
way through the entire brothel,
that is a bad decision
that could haunt you for life.
There are things in life
that you absolutely do not want to do,
and the
mistakes of those will haunt you forever.
But do you know what won't haunt you
forever? An underperforming video.
And even if it does underperform, even
if it does bomb, even
if you make a mistake
in the edit,
I've had it before where I've had mistakes
in the edit where I'm
literally sweating at home thinking,
"Oh my God, people are going to think I'm
terrible at editing." And the truth is,
no one cares. Literally, no one cares.
There was a study performed in a lecture
theater where
students were to walk into the lecture
hall late,
and they see everyone looking at
them, and they think it's so embarrassing,
and they sit there in their seats, and
pretty much everyone's going to think,
"Oh my God, everyone's going to think I'm
some kind of imbecile.
I couldn't even make it to the class on
time." But when the
researchers were to actually interview the
people, they said how many people turned
up late, the number was often wrong,
and all the people that went in,
they had a
design on their T-shirt,
and no one could recall what
was even on the T-shirt.
People are so caught up with their own
bullshit and their own world that even if
you arrive late with a funny design on
your T-shirt, no one even sees it because
they don't care. They
are too caught up with their own shit.
So even if 95% of the people
that watch a video aren't that interested,
there are
5% of people there
that you have an opportunity to help.
Every day you're not making videos,
you're missing out on people
that you can help.